# PATRICK COLE

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## CONTACT



Bradenton Beach, FL



+1 941 462 4590



patrick.cole89826@gmail.com

# **PROFILE**

Talented computer programmer with 10 years of experience in architecting, implementing, leading, and launching software products.

Have extensive experience in dozens of programming languages and platforms and always striving to learn more. Interested in a wide range of software engineering topics and always on the lookout for new and exciting projects. Well suited for the industry and bringing ideas to life.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Tech Lead | Full-Stack Developer - Bilbo

Mar. 2021 – Present

- Led the development team under three different workstreams.
- Developed microservices, APIs, and micro frontends for enterprise-level applications.
- Designed and developed core business functionalities for a US-based real estates corporation.
- Created and maintained more than 20 applications with ES6+, React.js, Angular, Vue.js, Node.js, Web3 and mobile development technologies.
- Focused on CMS development such as Shopify and WordPress.

Technologies: .NET, C#, Azure, TypeScript, React, Angular, Vue.js, Node.js, Web3, Microservices, Micro Frontends, Docker, Microsoft SQL Server, Kubernetes, Kafka, Shopify, WordPress, Low-Code Builder, Ruby

# Software Engineer - Bancambios

Feb. 2019 – Jun. 2022

- Successfully implemented 7 backend services and infrastructure to power core blockchain-based products in 8 months.
- Built security into new product features to achieve 100% compliance with industry best practices.
- Collaborated with external programmers to coordinate the delivery of 6 new software applications.
- Maintained customer satisfaction with forward-thinking strategies focused on addressing customer needs and resolving concerns.
- Participated in 3 NFT marketplace development projects and was instrumental in their success.
- Developed, tested, and deployed a manufacturing executing system (MES) for three large factories in the hydraulic industry. The system included production planning, execution, reporting, warehouse, and shipping.
- Led, designed, developed, tested, and deployed as a project leader an overall equipment effectiveness (OEE) monitoring system for monitoring the performance of the machine park in a factory in the automotive industry.

Spearheaded, designed, developed, tested, and deployed a machine traceability system for logging all
parameters from the machines, including test results, setpoints, component information, and more, in a
factory in the automotive industry.

Technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Relational Database Services (RDS), MySQL, Node.js, Python, BigQuery, Spark, Hadoop, Angular, Microsoft SQL Server, .NET, C#, Ruby on Rails, Elixir, GoLang

# Software Engineer – Swift Moving

Oct. 2015 - Nov. 2016

- An early stage startup in the B2B payments space; was fully responsible for all aspects of the technology solution.
- Provisioned and administered Linux virtual machines on AWS.
- Developed web apps in JavaScript on Node.js and Angular.
- Implemented file processing with Python.
- Worked on MySQL data modeling, SQL programming, and database administration.

Technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Relational Database Services (RDS), MySQL, Node.js, Python, BigQuery, Spark, Hadoop, Angular, Microsoft SQL Server, .NET, C#

# Software Developer – Ranosys

Aug. 2014 - Nov. 2018

- Maintained a 100% 5-star rating in 12 projects.
- Developed company procedures and guidelines for data analysis and security that increased efficiency by 30% in the first 6 months after implementation.
- Participated in over 250 code reviews to ensure code quality and received mentoring from senior developers.
- Designed, built, and automated data flows to save 10+ hours of tedious work per week.
- Applied hands-on learning and agile development to build MEAN and MERN stack applications.
- Developed Unit and E2E test cases using Jasmine, Jest, Mocha and Grunt, Node.js.
- Solved difficult dataset problems using ideas from distributed computing, large-scale design, real-time data processing, data storage, artificial intelligence, and machine learning, saving 35% on maintenance costs.
- Redesigned and rebuilt over 20 companies' websites and mobile apps, and resulted in remarkable growth for over 10 startup companies.
- Gained experience with various web development tools, including Bower, NPM, Git, Material Design, Gulp, and Cloud Services like AWS, Azure, GCP, Heroku and so on.
- Built a web-based WYSIWYG visual designer (Kococonnect) for mobile applications and embedded mobile experiences using React, React-Redux, and TypeScript.
- Devised and implemented the WYSIWYG Experience Editing Platform.

Technologies: Microsoft Dynamics CRM, Web API, Bower, Grunt, Scrum, SignalR, React, Office 365, SpecFlow, Selenium, TypeScript, AngularJS, ASP.NET MVC, Microsoft Azure, React Native, Android, iOS

### Freelance Developer – ELANCE & ODESK

Apr. 2012 – Jun. 2014

- Developed (hands-on) full-stack web projects, distributed systems, and services.
- Conducted research for customer intelligence related to eCommerce and online marketing solutions for well-known brands.
- Managed multiple projects and products driving them to a successful outcome.

Technologies: TypeScript, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, PHP, Linux, Refactoring, Continuous Integration (CI), Architecture, RESTful Services, RESTful APIs, Object-oriented Design (OOD), Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Automated Testing, Jasmine, Instruction & Coaching

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Information Technology – James Cook University (2013 – 2014)

GPA: 3.8 / 4; Certifications in Business Informatics

Bachelor of Information Technology – James Cook University (2010 – 2012)

Computing

## SKILLS

#### Languages

C, C#, TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, Java, Kotlin, HTML, XML, Python, Ruby, Elixir, CSS3, Liquid, Objective-C, Swift, GoLang

#### Frameworks

.NET Core, Angular, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), ASP.NET, ASP.NET Web API, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web Forms, Redux, AngularJS, Knockout, Kendo UI, Selenium, SpecFlow, NativeScript, Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), Spring, WWF, Xamarin, Vue.js, Ember.js, Ruby on Rails, Flutter, Electron, Gatsby, Django, Node.js

#### Libraries/APIs

jQuery, Selenium WebDriver, NgRx, Web API, Entity Framework, Graph API, RxJS, NServiceBus, React Soft Skills

Agile development practices, Code Review, Problem Solving, Time Management, Planning and Estimation, Multitasking, Teamwork, Collaboration, Communication, Attention to Detail

### **Paradigms**

Test-Driven Development, Design Patterns, Unit Testing, Data Science, Model-View-View Model (MVVM), Scrum, Microservices, RESTful Development